肯德基英语网www.kfcen.com提供下载
学习视频，中英双语高清字幕手机电影!
随时随地学英语，一切为了学好英语!
-2
肯德基英语网www.kfcen.com提供下载
学习视频，中英双语高清字幕手机电影!
随时随地学英语，一切为了学好英语!
-1
肯德基英语网www.kfcen.com提供下载
学习视频，中英双语高清字幕手机电影!
随时随地学英语，一切为了学好英语!
-=肯德基英语网www.kfcen.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径
我是杰克.莫斯里探员 编号227
This is Detective Jack Mosley. Shield number 227.
我想这将是我最后的遗言
I guess this will be my last will and testament.
这是给戴安的
This is for Diane.
今天一切结束之后 他们就会去找你把事情告诉你
When this day is over, they're gonna come and talk to you about this...
然后他们会... 他们会告诉你发生了什么，戴安
...and they're gonna... They're gonna tell you what happened, Diane.
但是他们所说得，并不是真正发生的事实
But what they tell you is not really what happened here.
所以，我希望你可以听到这些话
So I hope that you get this.
我是想做一件好事
I was trying to do a good thing.
片名：《16街区》
警察！趴下！全部都趴下！
Police! Get down! Everybody, down!
趴下！趴下！
Down! Get down!
走，进去，进去！快点！
Go, go, go! Come on!
- 没人 - 是警察， 给我趴下
- Clear. - Police. Get down.
给我封锁出口
Seal it off.
这里一切安妥了
Agent 10-10, we're all secure.
好了，我们收队吧
All right, we're out of here.
一切正常
It's clear.
你闻到那阵味了吗？
You smell that?
死了几个小时，我们得抓紧时间了 你能不能把那东西关掉？
Couple hours. We gotta move now. Would you turn that thing off?
好了，楼下的哪个我们用不着的？
All right, who's downstairs we don't need?
都交给你了，好运
It's all yours. Good luck.
我也不想这样，杰克 但我需要你留在这儿，等法医来
I hate to do this, Jack, but I need you to sit on this until uniforms get here.
- 好的 - 他们来了你就可以走了
- All right. - Just hang until you're relieved.
好的
All right.
别碰任何东西
Don't touch anything.
嫌犯说了什么吗？
Any word on the suspects?
- 你想要我告诉你什么？ - 你跟他们说了什么？
- What do you want me to tell you? - What did you tell them?
我看到有人在外面
I saw someone out there.
好，好，过来
Yeah, yeah. Come on.
- 有什么东西给我吗？ - 口气清新剂
- Anything for me? - Breath mints.
加诺瓦警官打来电话 他要你帮他填好这张汇款单
Sergeant Cannova called. Wants you to write up this wire request.
他让你这次不要再把日期搞错了
Said to make sure you get the right dates on them.
具体的事项放在你桌上了 他今天晚上就要
The particulars are on your desk, and he needs it by tonight.
好的
All right.
好，明天早上8点，我们可以派一个警官去
All right, well, we can have an officer come by about 8 a.m. Tomorrow.
你给她说派两个人过去？
You gave her two?
你知道，我们只做我们力所能及的
Well, you know, we do what we can.
嗨，杰克，忘了告诉你 中尉在找你
Hey, Jack, I forgot to tell you, the lieutenant's looking for you.
他要你马上去找他
He wants you to find him right away.
知道了，知道了
Yeah, yeah.
嗯，听着 好了，我等会儿再联系你
Well, listen. All right, well, I'll call you.
嗨，莫斯里
Hey, Mosley.
- 莫斯里. - 嗯
- Mosley. - Yeah.
格丽丝有没有让你找我？
Grace tell you to find me?
- 是的，一分钟前 - 好的，帮我个忙
- Yeah, just a minute ago. - All right, need a favor.
把这个人从拘留所押到中心大街
Get this guy from lockup and run him to Centre Street.
检察官要他马上去 他必须在十点前到法庭上作证
The DA needs him ASAP. He's gotta be in front of a grand jury before 10.
我已经下班了
I signed out.
你已经签出了？
You signed the sheet?
还没有,但是我马上就要去 我已经下班了
Well, not technically, no. But I mean, I'm signed out.
那就当加班吧
Then consider yourself on overtime.
古博队长打来电话 我们一定要把这件事情办好
Captain Gruber called. We need this thing done.
你手下没有什么别的人可以做这件事情？
Don't you got some mutt that takes care of this?
有基南，但是他还在办亚利桑那的那件案子 翻车的那件事
I got Keenan, but he's still on the Verrazano. He's behind some overturned truck.
我很累了，你知道，一般来说 我不会拒绝你的
I'm tired. I mean, look, normally, you know me, I don't say no.
我知道你忙了一晚上，杰克...
I know you been working all night, Jack...
但这里谁说了算？
...but who's the detective and who's the lieutenant here?
我是想说，杰克，我没有别人可以做这件事了
I mean, Jack, I got nobody else.
这不是什么大不了的事情
It's a nothing thing.
就花两个小时，过16个街区
One hundred and eighteen minutes to get a little hemorrhoid 16 blocks.
你明天可以晚点上班
I'll let you come in to work late tomorrow.
好吧，好吧
Yeah, yeah.
爱德华.本克
Edward Bunker.
嗨，警官，是我 我就是爱迪.本克
Yeah, that's me, officer. Eddie Bunker, right here.
在这里，最里面的一间
Down here, the last cell.
- 你过一个小时再来吧 - 你什么意思，过一会儿再来？
- Come back in an hour. - What do you mean, come back?
他要穿好西装才能走
He's supposed to wear a suit when he leaves.
- 然后？ - 西装还没有送到
- And? - It's not here yet.
现在就把他给我弄出来，好不好？
Just get him out here, all right?
他们说，他一定要穿西装
They said he'd wear a suit.
不，对，我应该穿西装 是三件式的，灰色的
No, yeah, I'm supposed to get a suit. It's a three-piece suit. It's gray.
是... 等等，呃
It's got... Wait. Yeah.
是三钮式的，灰色的 裤子是翘边的
It's a three-button, it's gray, it's got cuffs on the pants.
他们给我带来了样本目录 我从里面选了一件
They brought the catalog down. I picked it out of the catalog.
我不穿西装，不能走的，等等
I'm not supposed to leave without it. Wait.
我不能不穿西装就走
I'm not supposed to leave without that suit.
- 你自己跟他说 - 你不能让他这样做的
- You tell it to him. - No, that's why you brought my shoelaces.
- 来来，过来 - 我不能就这样出去
- Come on, come on. - I'm not supposed to.
- 喂，你说的那个故事，你会带老妇人走的，对吗？ - 嗯，你肯定？
- Yo, yo, you take the old lady, right? - Yeah, you sure?
一定要让老妇人上车，不然她就死定了
The old lady goes into the car, otherwise she dies.
- 确定？ - 我是这样想的
- You think so? - Yeah, man.
你再想想看呢？
That's what... I don't know. You gotta figure out the answer for yourself.
两位警官，你们听我说，我要去上法庭
Everybody just calm down. Officer, I'm going to court.
- 我需要一套西装才能上庭 - 喂
- I'm supposed to have a suit. - Hey.
给我闭嘴，这是你的东西
Shut up. Here's your property.
- 这不是个好兆头. - 把手放在你的背后
- It's not a good sign. - Hands behind your back.
- 等等，我还要... - 手放到后面来
- Hold on, I'm trying... - Hands behind your back.
我还没有我的... 所有我的东西... 就等一分钟
I don't even have my... All my prop... Wait one minute.
这样不对 他们答应给我一件西装的
It's not right. They promised me the suit.
我从目录里面挑出来了一件的 等等，我的书
I picked it out of the catalog... Wait, my book.
这本书可不能掉了，对我来说，他很重要
I can't leave without my book. My book is very important to me.
你这么着急干什么？这不是个好兆头
Why are we rushing like this? It's not a good sign.
- 喂 - 到底是怎么个结果？
- Hey. - What's the damn answer?
- 喂！ - 闭嘴！
- Hey! - Shut up.
- 我讨厌警察 - 汽油还有一半
- I hate police. - Half a tank.
你就不能再等一会？
You could have had a little more patience.
这套西装可以对你来说没什么 你大概有一堆西装
This suit don't mean nothing to you. You probably got a bunch of suits.
但是对我却非同小可
But it's a whole different thing to me.
警车怎么都是这种样式？
These cars don't ever change, huh?
总是这一种车型
Traditional cruisers.
座位设计不合理
And the same retarded hump in the middle.
味道也总是那么难闻
Smell the same way, like Lysol and vomit.
这种味道让人呕吐 估计有人已经吐过
I hope nobody vomited back here. They probably did.
喂，老兄，问你个问题
Hey, man, let me ask you something.
我在想一个问题
I'm trying to figure this out.
你正在路上开车，突然刮起了龙卷风
You driving along in your hurricane, right?
有三个人在路边
There's three people at the bus stop.
一个是老奶奶，她病了，就快死了
Yeah, one is an old lady. She's sick, she about to die.
第二个是你最好的朋友
The second one is your best friend.
他救过你的命
He saved your life, right?
第三个是你的梦中情人
And the third is the girl of your dreams.
然后，是这样的...
Right, but check it out...
你的车只能再坐下一个人
...you only got space in the car for one person.
就这样，你会让谁上车？
Right? Who you take?
这可以说是一个性格测试
It's a riddle that's supposed to tell what type of person you are...
可以看出你是怎样一个人
...like where you at in your life.
你用不着这么严肃吧，老兄，只是一个假设
It's a hypothetical question, man, damn.
只是个假设而已
It's just a hypothetical...
好吧，好吧 我猜我知道你的答案了
Well, good. Fine, good. I guess that's my answer.
你为什么不开扩音警笛？
Why don't you get on the loudspeaker?
或者把警灯打开？
Put the Hawaii Five-0 light on or something.
显示一下你们警察的权威 按一按警笛
Use your police power. Put on a little siren.
让前面的车子都让开
Make room, make a hole.
你们警察不是最喜欢说，“闪开，闪开”？
Isn't that the saying, "Make a hole, make a hole"?
让他们靠边啊！
Go on, make a hole.
征兆，到处都是，都是征兆，征兆啊 处处都是
Signs. Everywhere, signs, signs, signs. All over, man.
我以前注意不到它们的
I used to not even see nothing like that, man.
后来我慢慢能够看到一些
And then I start seeing them. And I start looking for them.
到最后我发现一切是注定的
And everything just start falling in place.
我会没事的，直觉告诉我
I'm gonna be all right, where I'm supposed to be.
虽然没拿到我的西装 但一旦作证完毕
I ain't got my suit, but once they get my testimony...
他们就会撤消对我的指控，我就自由了
...they drop my charges, I'm free.
我觉得这是合理的
It's making sense to me.
我相信一定会那样的
I believe in that.
这是我的命
Being in the right place.
你相信命运么？
Being where you supposed to be. You believe in that?
我相信人生太漫长 而且有你这种人，让我更受煎熬
I believe life's too long and guys like you make it even longer.
太漫长？
Life's too long?
你不是说真的吧
Damn.
我从来没听人说过这样的话
That's some cold shit, man. I ain't never heard nobody say no shit like that.
人们总是想活得长点，你说对吧？
Usually you hear about people trying to make their life longer, you know?
而且他们用尽一切办法活得久一些 你看上去有点...
Trying to stay alive a little longer. You sound a little...
有点悲观，你还好吗？
...depressed or something, you all right?
你为什么停下了？
You stopping?
这里不是法院，老兄 你在干什么？
This ain't the courthouse, man. What you doing?
喂
Yo.
喂，你为什么停车？
Yo, why you stopping?
你应该送我去法院 你干嘛？
You gonna rush me out to court, and now you stopping? What are you...?
嗨，嗨，老兄
Hey. Hey, man.
嗨，老兄，听我说， 我上庭之后还有一个重要的约会
Hey, man. Listen, man, I got an important appointment after my court date, man.
不要和我开玩笑 拜托，老兄，这可不是做游戏
That shit ain't funny, man. Come on, man. It's not a game, man.
喂
Yo.
该死的
Some bullshit, man.
喂，喂！
Hey. Hey!
哦，不，你可太不负责了
No, man. It ain't Miller Time, man.
上午天气很晴朗 但是下午...
The weather will be clear early morning, but the rest of the day...
山姆，安吉娜，你们好！
Sam. Hey, Angela.
总的来说，今天会是闷热而潮湿的一天
So we are looking at a hot, humid day.
气温可能会攀升到100度
Looks like temperature might reach 100 degrees...
所以出门的时候，别忘了带你的防晒油
...so don't forget to pack your sunscreen.
给我个袋子装起来，好吗？
Add a pack of these, will you?
我就觉得这个老兄奇奇怪怪 真是倒霉
I know this dude smelled funny. I got the wrong dude, man.
17块5
17.50. What?
嗨，先别开，来，拿过来
Hey, don't open it. Come over here.
都几点了
What time is it, man?
8:11了
It's 8:11.
还好，还好
That's a good sign. That's a good sign.
我都上路了，我一定会准时到法院的
I'm on my way. I'm gonna get there.
- 要找零？ - 不，不用找了
- Want change? - No, you keep the change.
不用找了 好的，一切顺利
Keep the change. All right, you have a good day.
- 我不要花生 - 拜拜
- I don't want the peanuts. - Bye.
不，老兄，我什么也帮不了你，明白？
No, man. Can't do nothing for you, understand?
嗨，你还是把那找钱给我吧 我可能需要点零钞
Hey, you better give me that change. I'm gonna need that.
你自己看看吧？
You see my situation right here?
不，不，不！
No, no, no! No, no, no!
嗨！
Hey!
我怎么出去啊？
How am I supposed to get out?
- 快点 - 帮帮我，帮帮我
- Come on. - Help me. Help me.
- 我的书！告诉你别停下的！ - 左边，快跑
- My book. Why did you stop? - Go, left, go. Left.
快，快，快！
Move. Move. Move.
等等，停下！
Wait. Freeze!
到里面去，快点
In here. Come on.
该死的
Shit.
喂！
Hey!
快点给我滚开，走开！
Just get out of here, now! Go on. Go!
来，我们走 那边，快，快
Come on, let's go. That way, let's go. Go, go.
这边
Ready? Here.
快点走
Let's go. Go.
- 多米尼克，让你的人现在就出去 - 老天呢，杰克，怎么回事？
- Dominic, get people out of here, right now. - Jesus, Jackie. What's going on?
- 所有人，包括你，都给我出去 - 好的好的
- Everybody. You too. - All right, okay.
- 我们走 - 来，快点走
- Let's go. - Come on, come on, come on.
Hey, yo.
快点，别停下，快点出去
Come on, keep going. Come on. Come on, move it.
喂，我是杰克.莫斯里探员 编号227
Yeah, this is Detective Jack Mosley, shield number 227.
这里有紧急情况，地址是...等等
I am 10-13, at... Hold on a minute.
- 多米尼克,这里地址是什么？ - 毛布里大街133号
- Dominic, what's the address here? - 133 Mulberry.
毛布里大街133号
133 Mulberry.
毛布里大街
Mulberry Street.
好
All right.
他们什么时候能到?
Is they coming?
我真是不明白，你为什么刚刚要停车?
I don't know why you stopped, man.
我真是搞不懂
I don't know why you would do that, man.
他们说你是个小毛贼
They said you were nobody.
- 显然不是这样的 - 闭嘴
- I ain't nobody. - Shut up.
你这酒鬼，你不能再喝了，知道么?
You a wino. You need to stop drinking, that's what you need.
给我闭嘴
Shut up.
杰克？
Jack?
- 弗兰克 - 嗨
- Frank. - Hey.
你还好吗？
You all right?
嗯
- Yeah. - Yeah?
我们在无线电上听到你的呼救
We were on Mott when the call went out. Heard it was you.
我们就尽快过来了
Got here as soon as we could.
哦，你好
Oh, hi.
- 嗨 - 你还好吗？
- Hey. - You all right?
- 嗯，我还行 - 好玩吗？
- Yeah, I'm all right. - You having fun?
- 不 - 不？那好吧
- No. - No? Oh, well.
应该挺刺激的
Gotta have fun.
- 怎么了，杰克？ - 嘿，老弟，嗨
- What's up, Jack? - Hey, man. Hi.
你做得很好，很不错，老兄
You did a really great, great job, man.
你干掉了第一个杀手
You got yourself a bad guy.
有一阵子没这样了，是吧？
Been a while, huh? Yeah.
我们在一个街区之外，抓到了第二个枪手 所以，一切都结束了
We got the second shooter half a block from here, so it's done.
- 你肯定你没事？ - 我没事
- Sure you're okay? - Yeah.
我一路跑过来，只是有点累
I'm just getting my wind. I was running.
接下来的事情，让我们来处理吧
Why don't you let us take it from here.
你们应该这样做
Oh, yeah.
我们知道怎么处理这小子的事情 你什么也不用担心
We'll get the kid where he belongs, and you don't have to worry about a thing.
- 你回家吧 - 对，拜托你们了
- We'll get you home. - Yes, please.
求你了，求你了，长官 这个主意太好了
Please, please, officer. That's a very good idea...
因为，老实说，我真的觉得这老兄不行
...because, honestly, I don't think this dude is doing too good.
我跟他说了，别停车
I told him not to stop.
我给他说不要停车，可是他不听
I asked him not to stop. He just had to stop.
然后那个人就走到我车窗边
That's when everything happened. Dude came to the window.
我上庭之后还有一个很重要的约会呢
I have a very important appointment aft...
杰克
Jack.
舒，你好
Hey, Shue.
来，给你
Come on. Here.
拿着这个，来
Why don't you take this. Come on.
我们送你回家，门口有辆车
We'll get you out of here. Got a car waiting. All right?
回家好好睡一觉
Get some sleep.
杰克？
Jack?
这小子要指证杰瑞
The kid was gonna testify against Jerry.
他看到了杰瑞的一些事情
He saw Jerry doing some business.
我们都知道，杰瑞不会像你我一样那么靠得住
Now, we both know that Jerry has never been a standup guy like you and me.
他什么都会说出来 我们不能让那样的事情发生
He'll roll over, they indict him. We can't have that.
那样会牵涉到我们中的很多人
No. It's gonna hurt a lot of us.
过来
Come on.
其实本来不该由你来送他去法庭的
See, this whole thing caught us... It caught us completely unaware.
本来是由Teach的外甥来开车送他
It was supposed to be Teach's nephew driving him.
但是他因为塞车，没赶上
But he got stuck out there in traffic, who knows where...
结果你上司就让你去了
...so then your lieutenant, he pegged you.
今天发生的一切 都只是因为错误的时间，错误的地点
You know, just the wrong time and the wrong place for you today.
仅此一次，下不为例 你也知道我从来没有这样为难过你，对吧？
All right. Now, you know that I would never put you in a position like this, right?
你可以理解，对吧？
You know that, huh?
我也没想到他们会失手
And I never figured you'd cap one of those guys.
- 他妈的一群瘾君子 - 拿住枪
- That's what I get for hiring drug addicts. - Grab the gun.
就是那样
Grab the gun. There you go.
就这样，弗兰克
Come on. Frank?
- 好了 - 好了，动手吧，杰克
- Here we go. - All right, here we go. Jack.
扳扳机
Squeeze the trigger.
好了，放开枪，快松手
All right. Let go of the gun. Let go of the gun.
我帮你想好了一个借口
I figure it like this.
你干掉了那几个杀手后
You... You pop the guys trying to spring the kid.
这小子趁你不注意抢了你的枪
The kid, well, he gets your gun.
然后还把你当人质
And he takes you hostage.
然后我们出现，搞定一切
So we came in and saved the day.
他死了，你没有
He died, you lived.
我觉得这样不错，杰克
Now, this could be a good thing for you, Jack.
对大家都好交代
Get you back where you belong.
- 你还跟那个谁在一起吗？ - 给我站起来
- Are you still with...? - Stand up.
- 她叫什么来的？ - 站起来
- You still with what's-her-name? - Come on, stand up.
- 快啊 - 她叫什么名字？
- What are you waiting for? - What's her name?
凯罗琳
Caroline.
她叫凯罗琳
It's Caroline.
这下一切都不一样了，杰克
This changes everything, Jack.
站到那边去
Over here.
快点，弗兰克
Come on, Frank.
小子，起来，快点
Kid, get up. Come on.
天哪
Shit. Man, shit.
杰克，已经8:25了
All right, Jack, it's 8:25.
- 你给我站住别动 - 你听我说，陪审团最多等到10点
- You stay there. - Listen to me, the jury's tenure ends at 10.
这小子只要迟到一分钟，这一切...
All right? The kid gets there one minute past, all this...
你做的一切就白做了
...it doesn't matter.
你再仔细想想
And all you gotta do is look the other way.
好吗？一切都还好商量
All right? We still got options here.
好吗？
Okay?
我们只要那个小子
We just want the kid.
杰克啊杰克，我可是在帮你
Jack, Jack, Jack, just let me help you.
好不好？
All right?
你给我退后
Back up.
杰克，一旦你走出那扇门...
Jack, once you go out that door...
我就帮不了你了
...I can't help you.
麻烦你退后，弗兰克 退后
Please just back up, Frank. Just back up.
他对警察开枪
He shot a cop.
你到底看到了些什么？ 看到了什么？
What the hell did you see? What did you see?
刚才那个警察
That cop back there.
我有次碰巧看到他...
I seen him around my way...
他把枪塞到那个可怜的波多黎各人的嘴里
...holding a gun in this little Puerto Rican kid's mouth.
快点，我们快点离开这里
Come on. Let's go.
他说，如果他出庭指证，就会杀了他的母亲
He said he'd kill his mother if he testified.
你那是干吗？我们需要那支枪
What you doing that for? We need that.
那支枪已经有20年历史了 刚刚是我们运气，它居然还管用
The shell in that gun was over 20 years old. Lucky it went off at all.
- 他们没有告诉你舒是个警察？ - 不，他们没有告诉过我
- They didn't tell you Shue was a cop? - No, they didn't tell me.
他们只是给我看他的一张照片
They showed me a picture, that was it.
这下好，恭喜你 因为你和纽约最阴暗的一面开战了
Well, congratulations, because you're about to testify against one of New York's worst.
- 什么？ - 兄弟们，时间在一秒秒过去
- What? - Fellas, look, the clock's ticking.
他们必须在十点之前到达法院 我们知道他们的目的地
He's gotta be at the courthouse by 10. We know where he's going.
毛利，你跟我来
Mulvey, you're coming with me.
- 知道你们该干什么了么？ - 我负责北边
- Know where you're going? - Take the north side.
- 明白了，我们走 - 快点
- You got it, let's go. - Come on.
- 上尉 - 怎么样了，弗兰克？
- Captain. - Where are we, Frank?
我们还没有让别区的人知道这件事情 只有本辖区的人知道大致情况
Well, we're putting descriptions out over precinct channels.
没有指明姓名，或者说其中一个是警察
No names, or that one's a cop. It'll help to have some eyes.
- 这件事，你能瞒多久？ - 他可开枪射击了一个警察！
- How long can you sit on this? - He shot a cop.
你是这个辖区的老大啊，丹 多久？
You're the precinct captain, Dan. How long?
我不知道，一小时，可能更短些
I don't know. Hour, maybe a little more.
- 都是什么人和你一起处理这件事？ - 都是我们的人
- Who's on this with you? - My guys.
66分队的奥蒂斯跟马多纳多 111分队的图西和凯乐
Ortiz and Maldonado from the 66. Touhey and Kaller from the 111.
还有一些你也没兴趣知道
A couple others you don't wanna know about.
那个人做了你搭档20年了
The guy was your partner for 20 years.
他很清楚我们的做事方法 他到底是怎么了？
What the hell happened in there?
- 他是不是喝醉了？ - 我不知道
- Is he drunk? - I don't know.
我真的不知道
I don't know. We woke him up.
希望他别多管闲事 这样我们大家都可以相安无事
Hopefully he'll do what he always does, and we can go back to work.
如果他不呢？
If he doesn't?
那我们要先下手为强，主动出击
We gotta quash this thing before he gets his legs back.
这里是他的地盘
These are his streets.
如果那小子开口，我们就惨了
This could get ugly for all of us if that kid talks.
- 他不能说 - 他不会说的
- He can't talk. - He won't talk.
你看，我很感激前面你为我做的一切
Look, I appreciate what you did for me back there...
但是我在想，你可能不适合送我去法院
...but I'm starting to think you're not the dude for this.
我是说，你上气不接下气，还喝醉了
I mean, you're out of breath, you're hung-over.
你说不定什么时候就倒下去了，老兄
Your leg is gonna give out on you any second, man.
我十二点一定要赴那个约，你明白吗？
I got someplace I need to be at 12, you understand?
所以十点前，我一定要结束法院的事情
I need to be finished at court by 10...
不然我就肯定会失约
...or I'm not gonna get where I'm supposed to get.
- 你明白我在说什么吗？ - 好了，我明白了
- You understand what I'm saying? - All right, I understand.
- 你根本没听我在说什么 - 等等，这边，这边走
- You're not listening to what I'm saying. - Wait, come here. Come here.
快点
Come on.
醉酒
Hung-over.
腿受伤了
A bad leg.
没枪
No gun.
- 波比？ - 在
- Bobby? - Yeah?
- 你知道我在怀疑哪个地方了么？ - 我知道了
- You thinking what I'm thinking? - I'm already there.
天哪
Oh, God.
快点，我们进去
Come on, let's go.
听着，你在这里站着别动 我很快回来
Listen, just stay put right here. I'll be right back.
快点，别太久了，我们必须马上走
Come on, man, don't take long. We gotta go.
抓紧点
Hurry up.
- 你洗手间在哪里？ - 什么？
- Hey, man, where your bathroom? - What?
洗手间在哪里？
Your bathroom. Where your bathroom at?
走廊尽头
Down at the end of the hall.
好的
Yeah.
你笑起来原来是这样
That's what you look like when you smile, huh?
可能也是喝醉了
You was probably drinking then too.
终于看到个女人
There's the lady.
红头发，很可爱，很不错
Redhead. She cute. That ain't bad.
老兄，快点，别停下来
Hey, man. Come on, don't be stopping to get high or nothing like that.
我们得快点离开这里
Man, we gotta go.
记住把厕板提起来
Make sure you lift the seat up before you go.
已经提起来了
It's up already.
你已经提起来了啊
Maybe you left it like that, huh?
我要来了
I'm coming.
嗨，杰克
Hey, Jack.
杰克.莫斯里
Jack Mosley.
你为什么那样做？
Why did you do that?
做什么？
Do what?
对那个警察开枪
Shoot that cop.
警察
Cops...
应该不会对自己人开火
...they don't shoot other cops.
尤其不会为了我这种小毛贼
Especially over nobody like me.
而且你并不认识我，你能这样做真是不容易
It's a long way to go for a stranger, you know.
谢谢你
Thank you.
从来没有一个人...
I never had nobody...
该死的，你知道的
Hell, man, you know.
我从来就不喜欢警察 你知道我的意思么？
I don't rock with the police, you know what I'm saying?
- 放开扳机 - 他们从来不是我的朋友
- Finger off the trigger. - They never been my friend.
- 然后你出现了 - 把枪扔到地上
- Then here you come. - On the ground.
可是你和其他人不同
It's kind of bugging me out, you know.
你不像其他的警察
You on some vigilante business.
这边走
Let's go.
- 杰克 - 两手抱住这柱子
- Jack... - Put your arms around the pole.
我都有点怀疑自己了
I don't know what to think anymore.
- 用这个，给自己铐上 - 你在干什么，杰克？
- Here. Cuff yourself. - What are you doing, Jack?
是啊，这是有些奇怪
Yeah, it's a little strange.
你知道么？这一切都让我有点不解
You know? By any definition, this here.
够了，小子，做得好
All right, kid. Good.
好的
Okay.
好了，好了，好了
Okay, okay, okay.
好了
Okay.
你不该这样做的，杰克， 你应该像你以前那样
You should have done what you always do, Jack.
- 你手机呢？ - 在左边口袋里
- Where's your phone? - It's on the left-hand side.
他们知道我来了这里 如果我不接的话
They know I'm here. If I don't answer it...
- 杰克？ - 我们走，小子，快点
- Jack? - Let's go, kid. Come on.
- 鲍勃 - 鲍勃现在不方便讲电话，弗兰克
- Bob. - Bob's a little tied up right now, Frank.
好了，杰克，你很让我吃惊
All right, I'm impressed, Jack.
你也对他开枪了么？
Did you shoot him too?
派人去救波比
Send someone to check on Bobby.
杰克，你不会成功的
Jack, you're not up to this.
知道吗？你不会有好结果的
All right? It's gonna end bad for you.
那小子跑了，对吧？
You lost the kid, didn't you?
他把你甩了？好吧，你知道吗...
He bailed on you. Well, you know what?
这是最理想的情况了
That is the best thing that could have happened.
我建议你回家
So why don't you go home.
忘掉所有的一切
Forget about what happened.
剩下的我们来处理
We'll take it from here. Are you looking for him?
你一个人是找不到他的
And you can't find him.
我们会找到他，知道吗？
We're gonna find him, all right?
我们会找到他
We're gonna find him.
好了，杰克，现在你可以挂电话了
All right, Jack, now you can hang up.
你小子跑哪里去了？
Where are you, kid?
好吧，现在，我们好好想想他会跑到哪里去
All right. Now, let's see which way he went.
他是要坐巴士，还是要搭地铁？
Did he go up? Did he go down?
在街上还是藏在哪里？他逃去哪里了？
In or out, Jackie. Which way did he go?
我们来看看他是不是去了地铁站
Let's see if he went down.
- 麻烦，先生，你能帮我刷一下卡吗？ - 去找个工作，兄弟
- Excuse me, sir, do you mind swiping? - Get a job, man.
夫人，你能刷卡让我进去吗？
Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in?
夫人？夫人，你能刷卡让我进去吗？ 求你了，夫人
Ma'am? Ma'am, would you mind swiping me in, please, ma'am?
我有一个非常重要的约会 我必须得...
I have a very important appointment I have to...
麻烦你了，夫人，你能不能...？ 谁能帮忙刷卡让我进去？
Excuse me, ma'am, would you mind...? Somebody mind swiping me in?
我要赶个非常重要的约会
I'm trying to get to an important appointment.
谁帮帮我，谁帮帮我
Somebody help me. Somebody help me.
谁帮帮我
Somebody help me.
喂
Hey.
过来
Come here.
- 来吧，从这里走 - 谢谢，太谢谢了
- Come on. Go. - Thank you. Thank you very much.
爱迪！
Eddie!
- 噢，不 - 你这是在干什么？
- Oh, no. - What are you doing?
- 你为什么逃走？ - 你想要什么？
- Why are you running? - What do you want?
你已经做得够多了，兄弟 接下来的我自己可以处理
It's too much, man. I'm doing the rest on my own.
我在照我自己说的做 我要离开这里
I'm doing what I said. I'm getting out of here.
- 如果我不找到你，他们会找到你 - 我在照我自己说的做
- Lf I can find you, they can find you! - I'm doing what I said.
爱迪， 听我说，听我说！
Eddie, listen to me. Listen to me. Listen to me!
- 我是唯一可以帮助你的朋友 - 不，你不是我的朋友
- I'm your only friend down here. - No, you're not my friend.
- 我能帮你... - 朋友？你根本不认识我！
- I can do this... - Friend? You don't even know me!
你带我去哪里？你会让我吃子弹！
And get me where? You gonna get me shot.
自从你出现了，就有人要想干掉我 你认识的人！
Ever since I've been with you, people been trying to shoot me. People you know!
听着，我有我必须去的地方 我有我必须做的事
Look, man, I got someplace I need to be. I got something I need to do.
除非你杀了我或者逮捕我 我要走了，杰克
Unless you gonna shoot me or arrest me, I'm going, Jack.
- 我不能让你走 - 谢谢你，杰克.莫斯里，我走了
- I can't let you leave. - Thank you, Jack Mosley. I'm going.
- 你不能走 - 我能走，谢谢你，杰克 莫斯里.
- You can't leave. - Yes, I can. Thank you, Jack Mosley.
不要这样，停下来
Stop. Don't do that. Stop.
你不能走，过来！
Ladies and gentlemen...! You're not going. Come here.
爱迪！
Eddie!
好，好，我跟你走
Okay, okay. Okay, we gotta go.
- 让开！让开！ - 别挡路！
- Move! Move! - Get out of the way!
让开！让开！
Move! Move!
- 这边，快点 - 你在干什么？
- Here, come on. - What are you doing?
出租车！嘿！
Taxi! Hey!
出租车！
Taxi!
凯乐说他刚刚在加奈路让他们给跑掉了
It's Kaller. He just missed them at the Canal Street station.
哪里，哪里，哪里？
Where, where, where?
妈的，你们到底在哪里？
Shit. Where the hell is he?
该死的
Goddamn it.
我们会找到你们的
We're gonna find you.
我是纽金探员，我需要你帮我定位一个手机
Yeah, this is Detective Nugent. I need a triangulation...
号码是917-935...
...on Detective Torres' cell phone. Area code (917) 935...
刚刚在你家的那个警察 他说你应该像你以前那样做
That cop back at the apartment, he said you should do what you always do.
他这样说是什么意思？
What did he...? What did he mean by that?
你没有像你以前那样做，对吗？
You're not doing what you always do, huh?
杰克.莫斯里，我知道了 我预感到了
Jack Mosley, I get it. I see the signs.
这一切都是注定 我以前错了，你是我命中的恩人
I'm where I'm supposed to be. I was wrong. You're the right guy.
我有可能碰上另外一个人 他可能就不会像你这样做了
I could have got another guy, did something different, but I got you.
我很感激你，你可以帮助我
I appreciate it. You're the right guy.
- 知道吗？ - 嗯
- Okay? - Okay.
- 这里是技术支援中心 - 对，我是纽金
- This is Comtech, over. - Yeah, go, this is Nugent.
全球定位系统显示他们在保利街
GPS indicates they're on Bowery.
重复一遍，保利街 目标在向南靠近培尔街
Repeat, Bowery, moving south towards Pell.
移动速度表明他们在步行
Speed indicates they're on foot.
大家听到了吗，他们在中国城
Are you hearing this, boys? He's in Chinatown.
我们都到那里去
Let's move in.
- 你为什么一直拿着那本书？ - 这是我的计划书，我想做点小生意
- What's the deal with that book? - It's my business plans.
我要去西雅图，我姐姐在那边
I'm moving to Seattle. My sister's already living out there.
我要开一个糕点店，不是一般的那种
I'm gonna open up a bakery. But it's only, like, a specialty bakery.
我的店只为小朋友做生日蛋糕 这样的店收入不错
Birthday cakes for little kids. There's a lot of money in that.
你过生日的话，我送你一个很大的生日蛋糕如何？
I'm gonna send you a big birthday cake on your birthday...
- 我讨厌生日蛋糕 - 你讨厌生日蛋糕？
- I hate birthday cakes. - You hate birthday cakes?
首先这不是你
First thing that doesn't go your way...
你会做的事情是偷偷闯入别人的理发店
...you're gonna be slipping into Carol's Clip and Curl...
然后偷走所有护发产品
...and stealing all her hair-care products.
因为你只会是一个小偷，爱迪
Because you're a thief. And that's what you are, Eddie.
- 你一直会是个小偷 - 人是可以改变的，杰克
- You're always gonna be a thief. - People can change, Jack.
- 日子能改变，季节能改变，人不会 - 人可以改变
- Days change, seasons change. Not people. - Yes, you do...
- 人是不会变的，爱迪 - 会的，我会给你那个蛋糕的
- People don't change, Eddie. - Yes, you do. I'll get you that cake.
你知道蛋糕上会写什么吗？
You know what it's gonna say on top?
"杰克 莫斯里，哈哈哈，吃了这个" 你那时就知道你错了
"Jack Mosley, ha-ha-ha, eat this." Make you eat your words, lick your fingers too.
目标沿培尔街向西移动
Subject's moving west on Pell.
目标现在上了道尔街，朝南移动 仍在道尔街上向南朝移动
Subject now moving south on Doyers. Still moving south on Doyers.
波比，你走道尔街，我们从培尔街靠近 凯乐，你从保利街包抄
Bobby, you take Doyer, we got Pell. And, Kaller, you close up Bowery.
- 收到 - 这下他们逃不掉了
- Copy that. - Let's squeeze him.
- 收到 - 把车停下
- Copy that, on my way. - Why don't you pull up. Pull up.
- 对不起 - 你们是谁？你们不能进去
- Sorry. - Who is that? You can't go in here.
噢，对不起
Oh, sorry.
听着，老兄，我们的方向是那边 你明白吗？
Look, man, I gotta be down there. All right, you understand?
我们应该下去，然后朝那个方向
I gotta be down there that way, and there's streets and shit in between there.
你有什么计划吗？你不是警察么？
You got some sort of plan? Some sort of police plan or something?
我看你跛得越来越严重了 你应该去检查一下
I see your limp acting up. You ought to get that checked out.
我有个朋友 也像你这样跛着脚走路
I have a buddy of mine walking around with a limp just like that.
但他不愿意看医生
He don't wanna go to the doctor, though, right?
最后他不得不去看了 他们说这是骨折
Finally he go, they say it's a fracture, right?
而且整条腿被感染了 膝盖以下都得被截掉
And now it's infected. They gotta cut it off at the knee.
这样也好，他不用那么痛苦了
Wasrt so bad, though. He had no more pain.
最后他去了新泽西州，找了一个工作
He ended up moving to Jersey, working for the PATH...
做火车司机，现在都他妈开始领养老金了
...being a motorman. Got a pension and shit now.
我认为每件事情都有它发生的原因 你懂我的意思吗？
I guess everything happens for a reason, you know what I mean?
你是个充满幻想的人 这就是我对你的评价
You're a sunny little shit, I'll give you that much.
进去！快进那扇门！
Get in here! Get in that door!
杰克！
Jack!
- 拉我进去！ - 快！
- Pull me in! Help me in! - Come on, come on, come on.
把门锁了
Lock the door.
- 慢点，慢点 - 撑住
- Wait, wait, wait. - Hold up.
快点
Come on.
- 你没事吧？ - 嗯
- You all right? - Yeah.
杰克，我们在做什么？我们要去哪里？
Jack, what are we doing? Where are we going?
- 快点 - 我们要去哪里，杰克？
- Come on. - Where we going, Jack?
让开
Out of the way.
过来这里
Over here.
杰克，这个是朝中心大街法院的方向？
Jack? How we even know that Centre Street Courthouse is in this direction, Jack?
杰克，确定是这个方向？
Jack? We gotta know...
趴下！头趴下！
Down! Head down!
走！
Go!
快点！
Come on!
凯乐！
Kaller!
推开它！
Push it.
你还好吧，杰克？
You all right, Jack?
我瞄准的是那个小子，不是你
I was aiming for the kid, if that makes you feel better.
那你没射中！
Well, you missed!
那小子会拖累死你的
That kid is gonna get you killed.
你觉得这样值得么？
He won'th that?
我可以一直这样和你拖延下去
Well, I got all day.
你呢，你有时间拖么？
How about you, you got all day?
- 杰克，你还在吗？ - 嗯
- Jack, you still there? - Yeah.
还在
Still here.
这有点棘手了
Well, this is awkward.
今天早上我开始上班的时候
When I started this day...
没有想到今天会和你开枪对射
...I never figured on trading 9 mils with my friend.
我想在8:25，那个酒吧里 我们就已经不是朋友了
I think we stopped being friends right around 8:25, in that bar.
不
No.
那不能抹杀掉我们一起工作的20年
No, that's not gonna erase 20 years together.
我们仍然是朋友
We're still friends.
听着
Look...
我也后悔过许多以前做的事情 可是这些都不能挽回
...a lot I'd take back, but I can't.
所以你只能向前看 新的一天，新的工作
Well, so you move forward. Next day, next case.
- 但是不能违背了原则 - 什么原则？
- Lines were crossed. - What lines?
- 你听到了么，不能违背原则 - 什么原则？根本就没有原则！
- You hear me? Lines were crossed, Frank. - What lines? There are no lines!
只有完成任务和完不成任务，就这样！
There's getting it done and not getting it done, period!
有时也许我们的方法很过分 但是我们也是在除暴安良
You put the bad guys away no matter what it takes.
现在，你将牺牲...
Now, you're gonna ruin the lives...
6个警察的生命
...of six cops.
他们都是好警察
Good cops.
善良的人
Good men.
为了那个小子而牺牲掉他们，值得么？
Are you ready to sacrifice their lives for that kid?
弗兰克
Hey, Frank.
- 弗兰克 - 嗯？
- Frank. - Yeah?
我没有想要牺牲任何人的生命
This is not about me ruining anybody's life.
懂么？而是因为你
Okay? This is about you.
听到我说什么吗？
You hear me?
嗯
Yeah.
你看过那个小子纪录了么？
You look at that kid's jacket?
我看过
I did.
- 持械抢劫，侵犯他人，殴打老年妇女... - 我从来没有持械抢劫过！
- Armed robbery, assault, beats old women... - I never had no armed robbery!
为了抢去社保金，他殴打一位老年妇女
Beats old women over the heads, steals their Social Security checks.
- 只有一次，我曾经... - 闭嘴
- One time, I used... - Shut up. Shut up.
噢，不，不要叫他闭嘴
Oh, no, don't tell him to shut up.
不，杰克，让他讲 那个小子，他很聪明
No, Jack, listen to him. No, that kid, he's sharp.
其实他在耍你
Yeah, he's playing you.
他比你聪明
He's sharper than you are.
他在唬弄你，知道吗？
He's telling you stories, right?
他肯定对你说他要做一个好公民
He wants to be a good citizen.
要上教堂
Go to church.
要为她母亲买房子
Buy his mother a house.
但实际上他一生大部分的时间都在监狱里
But he has spent more than half his life in prison.
两个小时前 他还因为非法持械被捕
Two hours ago, he was sitting in a cell for weapons possession.
- 他不会改变了 - 我没有...
- He's always gonna do what he has done. - I wasrt...
他是一个职业罪犯，而你却在保护他
He is a career criminal. That's who you're protecting.
- 你还好么？ - 嗯，弗兰克在另外一边对付他
- You all right? - Yeah. Frank's got him on the other side.
我的枪也被他抢了
He's got my gun too.
如果到现在，你都还执迷不悟的话...
Now, if you can't see how wrong this is...
我只能这样说
...I promise you I will speak from my heart...
我会在你的葬礼上为你念悼词
...when I give the eulogy at your funeral.
所以
So...
你相信那小子？
...do you believe the kid?
还是相信你的前拍档？
Or do you believe your ex-partner?
弗兰克，我们就在门的另一边
Frank, we're right on the other side of the door.
因为...
Because...
如果你相信他的话...
...if you believe the kid...
你必须做出选择
...you got a choice to make.
你要重新和你的搭档一起工作？
Do you go through your ex-partner?
或者你选择另一条路
Or do you choose door number two...
拖着你那条跛腿和受伤的手 继续和我们作对
...and go back to where you came, with your gimpy leg and your shot-up hand?
你不会成功的 而且万一我说的是正确的呢，杰克？
You're not gonna get very far. And what if your ex-partner is right, Jack?
如果我是正确的 那你做的这一切又是为了什么呢?
What if he is right, and you're wasting your whole miserable life?
- 我是弗兰克 - 你没事吧？
- It's Frank. - You all right?
我没事，他们在电梯里 封锁整幢大楼
Yeah. They're in the elevator. Seal the building.
跟上，波比 快点，我们上去
Come on, Bobby. Come on, get on that.
警察，所有人出去！
Everybody out! Police!
所有人出去！警察！ 快点，警察！
Everybody out! Police! Move, move! Police!
- 弗兰克，你在哪里？ - 波比，我上来了！
- Frank, where are you? - Bobby, I'm coming up!
好，快点 上楼，盯住楼梯间
All right. Come on, come on. Upstairs. Seal the stairwell.
- 好 - 你去逃生梯看看，检查一下屋顶
- All right. - Find the back stairs. Check the roof.
- 快点！从这里走 - 收到
- Come on, Mal! This way. - Got you.
- 马多纳多， 守在这里 - 收到
- Maldonado, seal it up. - Got you.
喂？喂？有人吗？
Hello? Hello? Hello?
- 没人 - 没有人回答，没人在，我们走
- No, nothing. - No answer. He's not there. Come on.
我从不开门
I never open door.
请，请帮帮我
Please. Please, help.
走吧
Come on.
杰克，杰克，谢谢你
Jack, Jack, Jack. Thank you.
- 谢谢，太谢谢了 - 太谢谢你了
- Thank you. Thank you very much. - Thank you very much.
- 你听到他刚才所说的了，对吗？ - 恩，他说他从不开门
- You saw that, right? You heard him, right? - Yeah. He never opens the door.
太谢谢你了，先生，谢谢你
Thank you very much, sir. Thank you.
- 谢谢你，太谢谢你了，先生 - 谢谢你
- Thank you. Thank you very much, sir. - Thank you.
- 你听到他说的他从不开门的，对吧？ - 知道了，爱迪
- You heard him, right, Jack? - Not now, Eddie.
- 小声点 - 他说他从不开门
- Keep your voice down. - He said he never opens the door.
你知道这意味着什么，对吗？
You know what that mean, right?
希望这不是坏的兆头
Not right now. There's the signs everywhere.
- 喂，请让副检察官马克当娜听电话 - 请问是谁打来的
- Yeah, ADA MacDonald, please. - May I tell her who's calling?
嗯，告诉她我是负责护送她的证人的
Yeah, tell her it's the guy that's got her witness.
你在飓风中开车
You're driving a car during a hurricane.
就是这个
Like:
飓风
A hurricane.
路边站有三个人
And there's three people at a bus stop.
- 一个老妇人 - 嗯
- A old woman. - Yeah.
另外一个是你的朋友，就像我俩
A friend, like my friend here.
你的这位朋友曾经救了你一命
Him. He save your life, your friend.
莫斯里探员打来的电话
It's Detective Mosley for you.
- 莫斯里？ - 喂？
- Mosley? - Yeah?
你在哪里？我的证人在哪里？
Where are you? Where's my witness?
我大约离你有七个街区
I'm about seven blocks from you.
但满街都是警察
But there's about a ton of cops between me and you.
他们每个人都想想要这小子的命
And they all want this kid dead.
况且还有你办公室里面的一个奸细
Not to mention that you got a leak in your office.
- 不断地向这些警察走漏风声 - 该死
- Somebody's talking to these cops. - Shit.
你当初起诉舒警官的时候 你就应该考虑到这些
What did you think was gonna happen when you pinched Shue?
你以为他们就束手就擒了？
You thought they'd just lay down and go away quietly?
我以为如果我们求助于大陪审团 舒会说出实情
We thought if we went to the grand jury, Shue would fold.
但他只是表面上妥协了
He bent but didn't break.
如果不是昨天晚上，我们发现了爱德华本克 我们已经放弃了
We were gonna throw it away until we ran into Edward Bunker last night.
陪审团最晚能待到10点，没有那小子 他们不会立案
Jury's tenure ends at 10. Without that kid, they'll vote no bill and it all goes away.
他是目击证人 是整个案子的关键
He's an eyewitness. He makes this work.
你在哪里？我派我的人过来 理查得，给我一支笔
Where are you? I'll send my squad. Richard, pen.
那个房间？
What room?
- 怎么样，他们来吗？ - 嗯，他们要来
- So, what, are they coming? - Yeah, they're coming.
太好了，庭审结束后我还有一个约会
Good. Because I gotta be somewhere, man. I got something to do.
我得在中午之前到那里 我一定不能失约的
I gotta be someplace by noon. I gotta go get something.
因为这是个很重要的约会
It's real important.
天哪
- Oh, shit. - Yeah.
奥蒂斯，我进来了
Ortiz, I'm coming in the building.
弗兰克？
Frank?
- 图西和凯乐没事了 - 很好，去找波比，他在逃生梯那里
- Touhey and Kaller are taken care of. - Good. Find Bobby. He's on the back stairs.
爱迪，过来，穿上这个 快点，穿上它
Eddie, come here, put this on. Here, come on, put that on.
这是羊毛衬衫 太热了，现在是夏天
But it's a big, hot, wool shirt. It's hot. It's summer.
- 你穿的是囚衣 - 哦，你想让我换衣服？
- You're dressed like a criminal. - Oh, you want me to...?
我明白了，但我想试试那件
You want me to change my...? I get it. But why can't I put that on?
- 这件怎么样？ - 那件怎么了？
- What about this? - What about that?
- 这件哪里不好了？你不喜欢它的样式？ - 这件太古怪了
- What's wrong with this? It's just a pattern. - He don't even wear that.
让你不要穿这件，别说了
Just put the... Here.
好吧，那这件怎么样？
Never mind. What about this?
这件还行吧？普通的蓝色？
Is this all right? Mass-transit blue?
我以前蹲监狱的时候 我曾在厨房工作
When I was locked up, they had me work in the kitchen.
有一天一个人过来跟我说
So one day a little dude walk up to me and say:
"嗨，你能帮我做一个蛋糕吗，我女儿生日"
"Hey, you think you could bake me a cake?"
我说，"好，可以啊"
I said, "Yeah, I'll bake you a cake."
你知道吗，那之前我从没做过蛋糕
I ain't tell him I ain't never baked a cake, you know.
我想反正我也没事情
But I ain't got shit else to do.
所以，我就照着食谱
So, you know, I read the instructions...
给他做了一个蛋糕
...I bake him a cake, you know, for his daughter's birthday.
后来她女儿来探望他，他把这个蛋糕给她
She'd come up there to visit him.
蛋糕上写着，"生日快乐，天使"
You know, it say, "Happy Birthday, Angel," right?
你不知道他有多感激我
He go crazy. He can't get enough, you know.
他说，"爱迪，你太棒了！"
He said, "Eddie, you done hooked me up. Man, you the man."
从那以后我就一发不可收拾
And I started doing that. It was good. I had a skill.
人们开始尊重我，他们开始...
People look at me different. They would start...
- 你少扣了一个扣子 - 是吗？
- You missed a button. - Did I?
你的扣子全扣歪了
Your buttons are all crooked.
- 快点，伙计 - 好的
- Come on. Come on, man. - All right.
纽金
Nugent.
真有你的
You're a prince.
- 房间是5E，伙计们，5E. - 收到
- The word is 5E, boys, 5E. - Got it.
然后我开始钻研做蛋糕的技巧
Then I start doing my research, doing my due diligence.
而且开一个专门做生日蛋糕的店 能赚不少钱
I found out, you know, it's good money in birthday cakes for kids, you know.
你可以把蛋糕做成各种动物的形状
That type of thing, like Tweety Bird or Bugs Bunny or something like that.
还有卡通人物雨果！ 你听过么？
Or Yu-Gi-Oh! You ever heard of Yu-Gi-Oh!?
- 雨果！ - 雨果！小孩子们都喜欢那个
- Yu-Gi-Oh! - Yu-Gi-Oh! Kids love that, man.
你不知道雨果！？ 你不知道他有多受欢迎
You don't know Yu-Gi-Oh!? You gotta get out more. Yu-Gi-Oh! Hot.
听到了么？
Know what I'm saying?
我会赚大钱的，杰克 经营我自己的糕点店
I'm gonna make money, Jack. Open up my bakery.
你会收回你之前对我说的话，杰克 我看上去怎么样？还不错吧？
You gonna eat your words about me, Jack. How do I look? Do I look all right?
- 好 - 不许动！警察！
- All right. - Freeze! Police!
- 警察！警察！ - 闭嘴！
- Police! Police! - Shut up!
- 噢，天哪！ - 闭嘴
- Oh, my God! - Shut up!
弗兰克，不是这个房间
Frank, they gave us the wrong apartment.
放下枪
Put it down.
快放下
你不会每次都那么走运的
Can't get lucky all the time.
但你干嘛不聪明点呢？
You can be smart every day, though.
- 好了，把枪给我 - 等等
- All right, give me the gun. - Hold on.
你在干什么？
What are you doing?
这里全都是警察，爱迪
This place is crawling with cops, Eddie.
嗨，看着我
Hey, look at me.
爱迪，你要干什么？
Eddie, what are you doing?
这种感觉如何？
How does it feel?
感觉如何啊？
你还要开糕点店对吧？
You're a baker, right?
爱迪，你听我说
Eddie, listen to him.
你开了枪，这辈子你都会坐牢
Pull that trigger, you go to jail for life.
弗兰克，我们下来了
Frank, we're on our way down.
弗兰克，你能听见么？
Frank, do you read me?
- 你们阻止不了我 - 我们该走了
- You can't stop me, you understand? - Time to go.
- 走吧 - 你们阻止不了我
- Time to go. - You can't stop me.
你居然给他了一把枪
You gave him a loaded weapon?
- 弗兰克. - 波比，快把手铐解开
- Frank. - Bobby, get these things off me.
- 他们拿你枪了么？ - 他们朝南走了，快追他们
- Did he take your gun? - They went south. Get out of here.
奥蒂斯， 给我一把枪 快给我一把枪
Ortiz! Ortiz, give me a piece. Give me a piece! Get over here.
让开，让开，快让开
Make a hole, make a hole. Come on, make a hole.
有人么？有人在么？
Speak to me. Come on, somebody, speak to me.
走这边
Turn.
- 对不起 - 开门！
- Excuse me! - Open up!
开车，快
Keep moving. Go. Go, go, go.
天哪
Oh, shit.
他们在公共汽车上，我们快追
On the bus! Let's go.
- 一直开，别停车， - 你干嘛？
- Just keep driving. - What are you doing?
- 我是警察，把后门锁上 - 他有枪！
- I'm a cop. Lock the back door. - He's got a gun!
别停下 告诉他们抓紧了，爱迪!
No stops. Tell them to hang on to something, Eddie!
别担心，他是警察
Hang on! Don't worry, this man, he's a police officer.
- 别担心，一切都会好的 - 抓紧了
- Everything is gonna be fine. - Hang on!
大家抓紧了，别慌张
Everybody just hang on. Don't worry!
右，右，向右转
Right, right, right! Go right!
- 你们在干什么？ - 快把车停下！
- What are you doing? - Stop this thing!
趴下！
Get down!
到一边去！离公共汽车远点
Get away from the bus! Away from the bus!
大家趴下，别动
Stay down! Stay down!
把头低下！
Heads down!
- 你们在哪里？ - 巴可士街的建筑工地
- Where the hell are you? - Construction site at Baxter.
他劫持有人质
He has hostages.
放了我吧
Let me go.
大家听着
Listen!
大家都站起来，他们不会向你们开枪的
Everybody, stand up. They're not gonna shoot you.
站在玻璃前面
Stand up in front of the windows.
他们不会对你们开枪的 你，蹲下，别站起来
They won't shoot you. You, stay down. Stay down.
全部站在窗子那里去，别留下缝隙
Fill in the blanks. Fill in the spots.
快点，快点，好的，就是这样
Scoot over, scoot over! That's it.
- 好吧，通知古博上尉 - 好的
- All right, get Gruber down here. - Okay.
喂！
Hey!
把那个出口封锁了
All right, seal off that end.
- 公共汽车上全是人 - 天哪，这下越搞越大了
- It's a busload. - Jesus, this shit just gets deeper.
- 波比? - 古博马上就到
- Bobby? - Gruber's on his way.
好吧，我们要口径一致
All right. We gotta get our stories straight, all right?
口径一致，知道了么？
We're getting our stories straight?
把防弹背心穿上
Yeah, suit up.
局长，这件事何必劳您大驾？
Thought we could handle this quickly and quietly, commissioner.
这个人朝警察开枪，还把一个大陪审团的证人劫为人质
A guy shoots a cop, takes a grand-jury witness hostage...
我们不能对他客气了
...and we're supposed to make nice?
局长，这...当心车门
Commissioner, look, sir, this is... Watch your back, sir.
这完全是我的错
This is my fault, all right?
我和莫斯里原来是拍档， 所以我让警长把这这个案子交给我
I used to work with Mosley, so I asked the captain to let me handle it.
我认为我可以捉住他， 但我没想到他会这样
I felt that I could bring him in. I just didn't realize how far gone he was.
- 随时待命，弟兄们 - 随时待命，好的
- Stay on Tac 2, boys. - Wait for command, here we go.
好的，把窗子蒙上
That's it, cover them up.
非常好，谢谢你们
Good, okay. Great job. Thank you.
- 局长，警长，你们好 - 迈克
- Commissioner, sir. Captain. - Hi, Mike.
- 情况如何？ - 嫌犯是一个警察，车上有20多人，这人是个疯子
- What do we got? - Cop. Twenty plus, flipped.
- 他有自杀倾向？ - 过去四年他接受了两次心理治疗
- Suicidal? - Been to the farm twice the last four years.
- 两次？ - 两次，但都没有这次这么极端
- Twice? - Twice. Nothing like this, though.
- 你的看法呢，侦探？ - 跟警长说的一样，他是个疯子
- What do you know, detective? - Like the captain said, he flipped.
他向舒开枪后，叫嚣要上头条
After he nailed Shue, he started spouting crap about making headlines.
这人相当的顽固
There's no way that you're getting this guy out.
请站到警戒线后面去，到人行道上去
Please fall back behind the barricades. On the sidewalk.
这是个很聪明的家伙
Smart cop.
好吧，你们都会没事的 我们马上放你们走
Okay. You're all gonna be okay. We're gonna get you out of here.
- 请到车的尾部去 - 杰克?
- Please, just move to the back of the bus. - Jack?
请走到车的尾部去，现在
Just move to the back of the bus, please, right now.
你们放心好了，我是一个警察
It's okay. You're gonna get off the bus. I am a police officer.
杰克，我是谈判专家迈克.希恩
Jack, it's Mike Sheehan from HNT.
我们几年前还共事过
We worked that barricade deal on the concourse a few years ago.
让我把这个扩音器放下
I'm gonna put this thing down, okay?
- 对不起 - 杰克!
- I'm sorry. - Jack!
对不起，我给大家带来这些麻烦
I'm sorry that I got you in this situation.
你很熟悉这一套了，我没带武器
You know the drill, no weapons.
听着，我只是公事公办
Listen, you're on the job.
- 把头放底点 - 你都知道这些步骤了
- Just keep your head down. - You know the deal.
我靠近一些了
I'm just gonna step in here, nice and easy...
我会把这个电话给你，然后我们就可以开始谈判
...and hand you this phone so we can talk, okay?
千万不要伤害人质 杰克，把门打开吧
Make sure we got no injuries in there. Jack, just open the door, okay?
- 我需要... - 扔过来好了，迈克！
- I need to... - Just throw it, Mike!
- 好的 - 扔过来！
- Okay, you got it. - Throw it!
接着，杰克
Here you go. Jack...
杰克，听到了么？
Jack, can you hear me?
车上有多少人？
How many people you got in there, Jack?
数数有多少人
Count how many people are here.
大家把手举起来，谢谢
Everybody put your hands up, please.
我们纽约警局，我们在执行公务 请大家回到人行道上去
N. Y.P.D., we got a situation here. We need you people back on the sidewalk.
- 不要越过路障 - 26，28个，好的，谢谢
- Stay behind the barricade. - Twenty-six, 28. Okay, thank you.
这就是所有的人了？ 请不要哭，不要哭
That's everybody? Please, don't cry, don't cry.
没事的，不要惊慌 冷静点，好么？谢谢
Everything's gonna be all right, just relax. Stay calm, okay? Thank you.
- 多少？ - 31
- What is it? - Thirty-one. Thirty-one.
好吧，这里大概有40人
Okay, we have about 40 people on the bus.
好的
Okay, that's good.
杰克，我对你直说好了
You know, it's important that we're clear with each other, Jack.
特警队和人质谈判小组都在这里
ESU and HNT are in place.
整个街区都被封锁了，杰克
The block is sealed, Jack. It's a frozen zone.
我们好好处理这件事情， 这样大家都好下台
So let's work this out so everybody can go home, all right?
这样对大家都好
That's all we wanna do. Just end it, nice and easy.
杰克？
Jack?
杰克？你还想怎么样，老兄？
Jack? This is as far as you go, buddy.
说话啊...
Keep talk...
- 大家还好吧？ - 嗯
- Is everybody okay? - Yeah.
- 你好，你怎么样了？ - 很好
- Hi, how are you? - Good.
你呢？
How are you?
我们名字叫爱迪 大家都还好？
My name's Eddie. Hi, how you doing? Everybody's okay?
你叫什么名字？
What's your name?
- 克里斯蒂纳 - 克里斯蒂纳
- Christina. - Christina.
那是个很漂亮的名字 你多大了？
That's a pretty name. How old are you, Christina?
- 七岁 - 七岁了
- Seven. - Seven years old.
我要给你做个草莓蛋糕 我知道怎么做，让我找找
And my strawberry recipe... I know I got one. Let me see.
我的草莓蛋糕呢？让我看看
Where's my strawberry recipe? Let's see.
这是怎么做天使蛋糕
Angel-food-cake recipe right here.
找到了，草莓蛋糕！
Here we go, strawberry fan.
看这个蛋糕的样子
See right here on the top?
我可以把它做成扇子的样子
I can put a fan on the top.
就是一个中国扇子的样子
You know, like a Chinese fan?
我可以把蛋糕做成那样
I could do that.
你什么时候生日？
Whers your birthday?
- 9月22日 - 哦，那很快了嘛
- September 22nd. - Oh, so that's soon.
就快8岁了，对吧？ 那是个很好的日子
Gonna be 8 years old, huh? That's gonna be a good day for you.
你的生日呢？
Whers your birthday?
今天，实际上
Today, actually.
- 是啊 - 祝你生日快乐
- Yeah. - Happy birthday to you.
是啊，每天都有人过生日
And, yeah, every day is somebody's birthday, you know.
我将来糕点店的标语就会是这个：
That's gonna be the motto for my shop:
“每一天都是一个生日”
"Every day's a birthday," you know.
没想到在我的生日会发生这样的事情，可是...
I didn't know my birthday was gonna turn out like this, but...
至少我还活着，我已经很高兴了
Yeah, I'm glad to be, you know, here, alive, you know.
- 说吧，杰克 - 希恩
- Right here, Jack. - Yeah, Sheehan.
局长
Commissioner, sir.
- 希恩? - 说吧
- Sheehan? - Right here.
好吧，这是我的条件
All right. This is what I want.
我要你帮我接通副检察官马克当娜
I want you to get me Assistant District Attorney MacDonald...
还有一位法庭书记员，和一位记者
...a court stenographer and somebody from TV.
我认识的记者
Somebody that I would recognize.
我要他们到车上来 帮我录一段证词
I want them to come on the bus and record sworn testimony.
这完了后，我会让每个人安全地离开
When I get what I want, I'll let everybody out. Safely.
- 我需要一些时间 - 别跟我来这一套
- That's a tall order. It'll take some time... - Just do it. I'm not in the mood, okay?
15分钟之类让他们到这里来
Get these people here in 15 minutes...
否则我会开始向乘客开枪
...or I'm gonna shoot these passengers one at a time...
- 然后把他们的尸体扔到车外 - 杰克，冷静点
...and throw them out the door. - Jack, be cool, okay?
别冲动，这件事情可以和平解决
Let's not do anything rash. This thing can end without bloodshed.
- 一切好商量，好么？ - 15分钟
- Okay? We can work this... - Fifteen minutes.
杰克？杰克？
Jack? Jack?
他挂了
He's gone.
好吧，大家都站起来
All right, everybody on your feet.
- 杰克，你干什么？ - 我得让这些人下去
- Jack, what are you doing? - Gotta get these people off this bus.
你不是才打了电话么？ 你让检察官来，他们不是同意了么？
But you just made your call. You called the DA. They said they'd come.
- 这些人都会来的 - 没人会来的，知道么？
- Everybody's coming. - Nobody's coming, okay?
没人会来？为什么？
What do you mean, nobody's coming?
5分钟内，他们会强行进攻这个巴士
They're gonna breach this bus in less than five minutes.
- 他们会杀了我，杀了你 - 杰克，我还要作证呢？
- They're gonna kill me, kill you... - Jack, what about testifying?
我们应该在这里等他们来 然后一切都会结束
We're right here. We can go. We can end this.
- 我们等他们来，然后作证 - 不会有人作证
- We can testify. - Nobody's testifying.
一切都完了，爱迪
It's all over, Eddie.
我们输了
We lose, kid.
- 雷 - 弗兰克.
- Hey, Ray. - Frank.
你们...?
You...?
你们要进攻了？
You guys going in?
局长还没有下命令
The commissioner hasn't given us the green light yet.
嗯，我要提醒你，他杀了两个警察
Well, I don't need to remind you that he shot two of us.
我知道该怎么做了
Enough said.
车上有40个平民 把他们救出来
We got maybe 40 civilians on that bus. Get them out.
不能让任何人受伤， 包括我们自己的人
I don't want anybody hurt, including our guys.
局长，没有人会受伤的 我们的突击队员都是训练有素的
Nobody's gonna get hurt, commissioner. These guys know what to do.
- 有情况出现 - 大家注意了
- We have movement. - Let's move in.
- 不要开枪，重复，不要开枪 - 朝汽车靠近，行动
- Hold your fire. Repeat, hold your fire. - Move in to the bus. Let's go.
喂，怎么了？
Hey. What...?
鲍勃.
Bob.
你出去的时候
When you get outside...
- 生日快乐 - 谢谢
- Happy birthday. - Thank you.
他们会把你带到一个隔离区 那里会很混乱
They'll take you to a holding area. It'll be hectic.
- 可是要是人人都出去了... - 听我说，你听我说
- But everybody's out there... - Listen to me, listen to me.
你一旦离开了这个封锁区 你便可以逃走
Once you get outside that perimeter, you just get lost.
- 可是如果他们？ - 不要停下，你一定不要停下
- What if they...? - Keep moving. You just keep moving.
听我说，你看起来不错
Come here. You look great.
喂，灰色西装哦
Hey, gray suit.
这可是你要的灰色西装
Got you a gray suit.
好了，大家把手举在头上，别回头
All right? Hands in the air, folks. Don't look back.
手举在头上，都结束了，结束了
Hands in the air, you'll be all right. You'll be all right.
下一位，对不起
Next. Sorry.
快，快，跟我来
Come on, come on, let's go!
- 他这是在做什么？ - 我怎么知道？
- What is he doing? - How should I know?
- 我现在不知道 - 你居然用这种口气...
- I'll let you know when I know. - Don't you...
我明白了自然会告诉你 滚开！
I'll let you know when I know. Out of my face!
凯乐，过来帮帮我
Kaller, give me a hand with them!
波比?这边，这边
Bobby? Right there. Right here.
- 就是他 - 喂，你干嘛？
- That's him. That's him. - Hey, man!
- 不是他 - 让他走吧
- It's not him. - Let him go.
- 他穿了别人的衣服 - 什么？
- The dude, he changed. It's not me. - What?
- 他换上了一套西装，灰色西装 - 灰色西装，好的
- He's in a suit, a gray suit. - Suit, gray suit.
- 有31人下了车 - 那车上还有8个人
- We count 31. - That leaves eight people on the bus.
不，我是最后一个人
No, I was the last one off the bus.
车上就只剩下那个拿枪的人
The only person left on that bus is the guy with the gun.
- 那你们行动吧 - 开始行动
- Then go, do it! - Let's go, let's go.
行动开始
- Get your people out there. Let's go. - Come on, let's go.
莫斯里还在车上 那个小子不在车上，我们搜查了...
Mosley is still on the bus. That kid is here somewhere. We checked...
波比，别废话了
Bobby, I don't care what you checked.
再给我搜一遍，马上 你们，去那边
Check it again, now. Go. You guys, that way.
我是警探杰克 莫斯里，警号227
This is Detective Jack Mosley. Shield number 227.
这可能会是我最后的遗嘱
I guess this will be my last will and testament.
别开枪！
Don't shoot!
Hold your fire!
别开枪！别开枪！
Do not shoot! Do not shoot!
- 那个人是谁？ - 别开枪！
- Who is that? - Hold your fire!
- 别开枪！ - 那个人就是那个证人么？
- Hold your fire! - Is it that wit from the 32?
给我查清楚那个人是谁
Get on your goddamn radio. Find out who that is.
别开枪！
Guns down, hold your fire!
Don't shoot!
别开枪！
Don't shoot! Don't shoot!
Don't shoot!
别开枪！
- 站住！不要靠近那部汽车！ - 别开枪！
- Do not move! Step away from the bus! - Don't shoot, hold your fire!
- 别开枪！ - 离开公共汽车！
- Do not shoot! - Get away from the bus!
别开枪
Hold your fire.
杰克，是我
Jack. Jack, it's me. Jack Mosley!
杰克，是我，爱迪
It's me, Eddie, Jack.
查克.贝里
Chuck Berry.
查克.贝里， 他因为抢劫入狱
Chuck Berry, he got locked up for armed robbery.
但是他后来改变了
He changed. He changed.
巴里.怀特，他偷了300各轮胎
Barry White, he stole 300 tires.
你能想象他偷了300个轮胎么？他后来也变了
Can you picture big Barry White stealing 300 tires? He changed.
你说...你说人本性难移
You said... You said people don't change.
- 但是实际上人会变的 - 爱迪
- People change. - Eddie.
- 怎么了？ - 你把我害死了
- What? - You're killing me.
第三组，行动 重复，第三组，行动
Team three, breach the bus. Repeat, team three, breach the bus.
第三组靠近汽车
Entrance team moving in.
让开！
Get out of the way!
把头埋下！ 遮住耳朵和眼睛！
Head down! Cover your ears and your eyes!
- 别开枪 - 跟进，跟进！
- Hold fire. - Go, go!
- 跟进！ - 别开枪！
- Go, go, go! - Hold your fire!
他到底要干嘛？
This is a nightmare.
别开枪！
Hold fire!
- 快点！行动！ - 当心！
- Let's go! Move, move, move! - Stay down!
- 过来，过来！ - 这里
- Move up! Move up! - Come here.
第二组，报告你们情况？
Team two, status?
快！
Go ahead! Take it! Go!
车上没有人
The bus is empty.
他们从前门逃跑了！
They went through the bus doors!
他们在这栋楼里！ 封锁这里！
They're in the goddamn building! Seal it off!
- 汽车上没有人 - 他们跑进了楼里
- All clear. The bus is empty. - They've entered the building.
封锁这栋楼，开始搜索
Seal the building, start a search.
当心，他杀了两个警察，你们要小心
Remember, heads up. He just shot two cops. Be careful.
杰克，我要告诉你一件事情
Jack, I gotta tell you something.
喂，杰克，听我说
Hey, man. Jack, listen to me, man.
杰克，我要给你说件事情
Jack, I wanna tell you something.
等等，我告诉你件事情 这很重要
Hold on, hold on, wait. I gotta tell you something. It's important.
振作点，我们走
Shit. Get up, go.
妈的
Oh, shit.
对不起，这位先生，我是一个警察 我在执行任务
Hey, sir. I'm a cop, all right? I'm on the job.
我借你的电话用下
Look, I need that phone for a minute.
看看你把我的西装弄成这样了
Look what you did to my suit, man.
我就知道你会让我中弹的
I told you you was gonna get me shot.
是我，我需要你的帮助
It's me. I need your help.
一切都是因为我朋友毛里斯
All this started because my friend Maurice came by my house.
两天前他到我家来
Two days ago, Maurice came by my house.
他那时很慌张
He all excited.
他手里拿着一个鞋盒
He got a shoebox.
他有把枪
He had a gun.
他对我说，“你帮我保管一阵子”
He talking about, "Hold this for me for a little while."
我对他说，“我还在缓刑期内呢” 他说，“我也是”
I'm like, "I'm on parole." He like, "Me too."
过了一天，他被杀了
Next day, somebody shot him.
鞋盒里面有三万两千块钱
Thirty-two thousand dollars in that shoebox.
- 那是个凶兆，对吧 - 是的
- That's a sign, huh? - Yeah.
那真是个凶兆
It's a very big sign.
当心
Easy, easy, easy.
你知道开个糕点店需要多少钱么？
You know how much it gonna take me to open the bakery?
三万一千块钱
Thirty-one thousand dollars.
杰克，当时我不知道怎么办 我就冲出房外
Jack, I got so nervous I ran out the house.
把这些钱藏在了汽车站的储物柜里
I went to Port Authority and I put the money in a locker.
当我回家的时候
I get back to my house...
我的缓刑辅导员在那里
...my parole officer's there...
就在我家里
...in my house.
他发现了毛里斯留下的枪
He got Maurice's gun in his hand.
他看着我，很失望的样子
He looking at me like, "That's it, Eddie."
他说这至少得判15年
And he's talking about 15 years, man.
我吓呆了
I got so sick.
后来检察官给我打来电话
Then the DA came to my cell...
他给我看了那个警察的照片
...and he showed me the picture of that cop.
然后就是你
Then I met you.
杰克， 每天他们都要清理那些储物柜
Jack, they clean them lockers out every 24 hours.
我的时间还挺紧的
I had a little schedule going, man.
10点钟上法庭作证
Court at 10:00...
12点赶到汽车站
...Port Authority at 12.
喂，看着我，清醒点
Hey. Hey, look at me. Wake up.
你不会在我面前死去，对么？
You ain't gonna die on me, are you?
我怎么知道，我从来没有经历过死亡
I don't know, I never died before.
你今天不会死的
It's not gonna happen today.
谢谢你来这里
Hey. Thank you for coming.
- 出什么事情了？ - 你看，他这里中枪了
- What's going on? - Look. Shot here. I think it went in and out.
好吧，我们把他抬到车上去
Yeah, let's get him in.
我认识你
I know you.
- 来吧 - 我去过你家
- Come on. - I was at your house.
- 你去过我家？ - 我得把我枪带上
- You were at my apartment? - Had to get my gun.
别说话了
Bigmouth.
你的房间很漂亮，很干净
It was very nice, very clean.
警察在医院盘问了我一个小时
The police grilled me for an hour at the hospital.
你对他们说了什么？
What'd you say to them?
我说你是个抑郁症患者
That you're a self-medicating, depressed individual.
我说你什么都能干得出来
And you don't care about anything or anyone.
她好坦率 这样很性感，我喜欢这样
Oh, she's honest, straightforward. That's sexy. I like that.
这次你又准备怎么做，杰克？
What'd you do this time, Jack?
他几次都救了我的命
He saved my life a couple times.
他是个好人 你应该再给他一次机会
Hey, he's a good dude. You gotta give him another chance.
我不知道他以前做了什么， 但是你应该再给他一次机会
I don't know what he did, but you gotta give him another chance.
他需要一个谈话的人
He gotta have somebody to talk to.
我可不能一直陪他
I'm not gonna be around.
- 爱迪，这是我妹妹，戴安. - 什么？
- Eddie, this is my sister, Diane. - What?
她是你妹妹？
She's your sister?
原来如此
Oh, man.
我才开始对你有了好感 可是你的家人都不喜欢你
I just started having a little hope for you. Your family don't even like you.
我也有一个妹妹
I got a sister too.
但是她在西雅图
But she live in Seattle.
我本来打算去那里开我的糕点店的
I was supposed to go out there and start my bakery.
我本来今天就该出发的
I was supposed to go out there today to see her.
她说到汽车站来接我的
See her on the bus.
我现在把血止住了
I can stop the bleeding...
但是我们必须到医院去 把伤口给他缝上
...but he's gotta get stitched up, get to a hospital.
我们需要在20分钟内到法庭上去
We gotta be at the courthouse in less than 20.
你必须得帮助我
You're gonna have to do it.
一切都会好的，爱迪. 这不像看上去的那么糟糕
You're gonna be fine, Eddie. It's not as bad as it looks.
你的手怎么了？
What happened to your hand?
看来你还得帮我个忙
I gotta ask you one more favor.
很小的忙
Just a little favor.
喂，今天真的是你的生日？
Hey, is today really your birthday?
不是
No.
我说今天是我的生日 因为我不想小女孩那么害怕
No, I just said that because the little girl, she was so scared.
她很可爱
She was cute, man.
你生日是多久？
Whers your birthday?
- 我不知道 - 你不知道是什么意思？
- I don't know. - What do you mean, you don't know?
真的，我不知道
No, for real, I don't know.
我是在孤儿院长大的 那里太多的生日了
I'm not... I came up in foster care. Had a lot of birthdays.
但是你说有一个妹妹？你今天要去见的
But didn't you say...? You got a sister, right? That you're going to see?
是啊，我几个月前才发现
Yeah, I just found out about her a couple months ago.
- 你见过她么？ - 没有
- Never met your sister? - No.
那也是我去西雅图的原因，我想见她
That's why I'm going out to Seattle to meet her.
我很期待
I'm looking forward.
说不定她长得像安吉丽娜.朱丽呢
Maybe she turns out to look like Angelina Jolie.
我可不希望她只是我妹妹
Shit, if she do, I hope she ain't my sister.
你想要蛋糕上写什么字？
Hey, man, what you want on your cake, man?
我会给你做一个蛋糕的
You never told me. I gotta send you one, man.
- 我不需要什么蛋糕，爱迪. - 别这么不给面子，老兄
- I don't want no cake, Eddie. - Damn it, Jack, come on, man...
我想不起...
I can't think of anything that has happened in my life...
- 有什么我想写在蛋糕上面的 - 一句话都没有？
...that I would want written on a cake. - Nothing?
我不是一个好人，爱迪.
I'm not a good guy, Eddie.
我不是一个好人
I'm not a good guy.
好吧，那我也不是
Yeah, me neither.
- 戴安 - 弗兰克
- Diane. - Frank.
把钥匙给我
Give me the keys.
- 呆在车里别出来 - 这里可不是你的辖区，不是么？
- Stay in the car. - Little out of your sector, aren't you?
救命可不分什么辖区
Saving lives knows no bounds.
- 这你应该很清楚， 弗兰克. - 你看上去气色不错嘛
- You should know that, Frank. - You look good.
你看上去有点绝望 这可不像你
You look a little desperate. Doesrt suit you.
把门打开
Open the door.
快把门打开
Open the door. Open the door.
对不起，杰克，我就只能送你到这里了
Sorry, Jack, this is as close as I can get you.
好吧，算你走运
Like I said, you're looking good.
谢谢了，兄弟
Thanks, kid.
好吧，我们去法庭上
All right, come on, let's go.
不，等下
No, hey, hold on. Hold on a minute.
为什么？还等什么？
Why is that? Hold on for what?
你就到这里为止了
This is as far as you go too.
- 什么意思？ - 听我说，爱迪
- Come on, man. I don't... - Listen to me, Eddie.
- 怎么了？ - 听着
- What? - Listen.
你要去指证的这些人
Those guys you were gonna testify against...
- 这些警察 - 嗯？
...those cops? - Yeah?
我就是其中一个
I was one of them.
也就是说，你要去指证我
You were gonna testify against me too.
他们做的，我都做了
I did what they did.
我知道那很坏
We did some bad things.
我利用了你
I did another bad thing when I used you.
其实根本不需要你来指证我们
I was gonna let you do what I should have done.
我若干年前就应该自首了
What I should have had the courage to do six years ago.
对不起
I'm sorry.
你知道，要是今天不是你的话
You know, if you didn't come to get me today...
我现在已经死了
...l'd be dead right now.
- 恩 - 所以...
- Right. - So...
今天我们见面
I was supposed to meet you.
是命中注定
That was the sign.
你救了我一命
You saved my life, kid.
保重了
Take care of yourself, kid.
谢谢你
Thank you.
你可以做糕点了，爱迪师傅
Make cakes, Eddie the baker.
哦对了，你把车钥匙交给你的朋友
Oh, yeah. You give the car keys to your best friend.
你让他带老妇人去医院
You let him take the old lady to the hospital.
你在车站等那个梦中的女孩，对么？
You stay at the bus stop with the girl because she's the girl of your dreams, right?
所以一切都会好的
So everything's gonna be okay.
- 对吧？ - 嗯
- Right? - Yeah.
西雅图生活愉快！向你妹妹问好
Have fun in Seattle. Say hi to your sister.
好的
Yeah.
好吧
你载他去汽车站 保证他赶上那班车
Get him to the Port Authority. Make sure he gets on that bus.
- 卡尔，多谢了 - 不用
- Carl, thanks. - No problem.
好的
All right.
真是糟糕的一个早上，对吧？
Hell of a morning, huh?
那小子呢？
Where's the wit?
他不在了
You're looking at him.
我放他走了，弗兰克
I let the kid go, Frank.
- 你抓不住他了 - 去你的
- You're not gonna get to him now. - Bullshit.
你干什么？
Wouldrt do that.
那...
So...
你要在法庭上怎么说？
...what do you think you're gonna tell them?
你要把所有的事情都说出来么？
Are you gonna tell them everything?
你要给他们说你也是一员么？
Are you gonna tell them about you too?
你觉得那样你良心就好受点了？
You think that's gonna make you feel better?
我怎么都不会好受点
Nothing's gonna make me feel better.
那你这是为什么？
Then why?
你听我说，杰克，你和我...
Look, Jack, you and me...
我们一直就是这样做事的
...we did our business in a certain way.
即使是那些很棘手的案子， 我们也心照不宣
You never complained when we cleared the tough cases.
你以前什么都无所谓，直到...
It didn't bother you doing any of that until...
听我说，好么？听我说
Listen to me, all right? You listen.
杰克，你听好了
Okay, Jack? Really listen.
你如果想在法庭上揭露真相
Whatever you think that you are gonna do up there...
我不会让那发生的
...it is never gonna happen.
你不会成功的
You are not gonna make it.
你这样想么，弗兰克？
Is that what you're thinking, Frank?
你要在这里杀了我？ 你以为没人会知道？
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
就像你杀掉林家一样？
Like the Ling family, huh?
你以为别人看不出来？
Like they never knew.
他是个傻老头 他自己管不住自己的嘴巴
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
好吧，是我把枪指到他嘴里
All right, so I stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
- 然后他心脏病发作了死了，又怎样? - 又怎样？
- He had a heart attack, he died. So what? - So what?
你听着，如果他没有心脏病发，他没有死...
Look, if it hadrt happened the way that it did, if he hadrt died...
你当初就不会拍着我背说，“做得好”
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, "Good job."
我们这一行，误伤总是会发生的
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
你在房间里清理指纹的时候，他还活着
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是无辜的
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was an innocent man.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是一个丈夫
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's husband.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是一位父亲
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's father.
他不死我们就会完蛋！ 我们不得不那样做！
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
- 他只是想把真相说出来 - 去他妈的真相
- He wanted to tell the truth. - Fuck the truth!
好吧
Right.
我再也不需要这个了
I'm not gonna need this anymore.
波比？他上来了
Bobby? He's on his way up.
干掉他
Take him out.
莫斯里在这里！快通知副检察官 别动！
Mosley's in the building! Get the ADA. Freeze!
- 举起手来！ - 别开枪
- Hands in the air! - Don't shoot.
- 别动！跪下！ - 我没有武器
- Don't move! Down on your knees. - I'm not armed.
- 跪下！马上！ - 别开枪，我没有武器
- Down on your knees! Now! - Don't shoot, I'm not armed.
别用枪指着我 请通知副检察官马克当娜
Lower your weapon. Just call ADA MacDonald, please, on the radio.
- 手举起来 - 让副检察官马克当娜到这里来，马上！
- Hands up. - Get ADA MacDonald here right now!
- 别开枪 - 把你的手举起来！
- Don't shoot. Don't shoot me. - Get your hands up!
请让副检察官马克当娜到这里来
Just get ADA MacDonald for me.
- 杰克，别耍花样！ - 废话少说，跪到地上！
- Jack, come on! - I won't argue with you. Get down.
莫斯里! 莫斯里!
Mosley! Mosley!
手举起来！
Hands up!
我的证人呢？ 爱德华.本克在哪里去了？
Where's my witness? Where's Edward Bunker?
他不能来了
He didn't make it.
我代替他作证
I'm gonna take his place.
- 请不要把枪对着我 - 你们把枪放下
- Please lower your weapons. - Hold your fire and stand down.
你们让开
Back off.
我有证据...
I have information...
证明有人想杀害你目前这个案子的证人
...regarding your ongoing witness-tampering investigation.
我还要提供证据 有关很多刑讯逼供的案件
Dates, cases that include extortion...
伤害甚至谋杀证人
...manslaughter and possible homicide...
这些案件涉及到14辖区的警察
...involving members of the 14th Precinct.
涉案人员包括丹.古博上尉
These charges include Captain Dan Gruber...
杰瑞.舒探员
...detectives Jerry Shue...
埃德华.麦多纳多
...Edward Maldonado...
鲍博.托里斯
...Bob Torres...
吉姆.马利
...Jim Mulvey...
还有我自己
...myself...
还有法兰克.纽金探员
...and Detective Frank Nugent.
你说这些是为了什么，莫斯里？ 你想要做什么？
What's this about, Mosley? What do you want?
我要还爱德华.本克一个清白
I want Edward Bunker's record expunged.
- 可以，还有其他要求么？ - 没有了
- Done. What else? - Nothing else.
你可以证明你说的一切么，莫斯里？
You can substantiate all this, Mosley?
是的
Yeah.
枪！
Gun!
别开枪，是我开的那枪
Hold your fire. I fired that shot.
你要在这里杀了我？ 你以为没人会知道？
You're gonna shoot me down here? Nobody knows?
就像你杀掉林家一样？
Like the Ling family, huh?
你以为别人看不出来？
Like they never knew.
他是个傻老头 他自己管不住自己的嘴巴
He was a stupid old man who wouldn't keep his mouth shut.
好吧，是我把枪指到他嘴里
All right, so I stuck a gun in some guy's mouth.
- 然后他心脏病发作了死了，又怎样？ - 又怎样？
- He had a heart attack, he died. So what? - So what?
- 又怎样？ - 你可知道他是一个无辜的人？
- So what? - So how about he was innocent?
- 无辜？ - 他不该成为牺牲品
- Innocent? - How about he didn't deserve to die?
你听着，如果他没有心脏病发，他没有死...
Look, if it hadrt happened the way that it did, if he hadrt died...
你当初就不会拍着我背说，“做得好”
...you would've been patting me on the back, saying, "Good job."
我们这一行，误伤总是会发生的
Collateral damage, it is a fact of life in this business.
你在房间里清理指纹的时候，他还活着
He took his last breaths while you were wiping the fingerprints off the room.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是无辜的
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was an innocent man.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是一个丈夫
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's husband.
- 他不死我们就会完蛋 - 他是一位父亲
- He was gonna take down our case. - He was somebody's father.
他不死我们就会完蛋！ 我们不得不那样做！
He was gonna take down our case! What were we supposed to do?
- 他只是想把真相说出来 - 去他妈的真相
- He wanted to tell the truth. - Fuck the truth!
我们带你到法庭上去
Let's get you to the jury.
- 谢谢 - 谢谢
- Thanks a lot. - Thanks.
好的
Okay.
- 生日快乐 - 生日快乐，杰克
- Hey, happy birthday. - Happy birthday, Jack.
欢迎回来，杰克
Welcome back, Jack.
- 你什么意思？ - 你在监狱里呆了两年，终于回来了
- Are you kidding me? - Two years in the pen is enough.
那可不是一段好的回忆
Thanks for that memory. Thank you.
- 生日快乐，杰克 - 生日快乐
- Happy birthday, Jack. - Happy birthday.
- 生日快乐，把蜡烛吹了吧 - 欢迎你回家
- Happy birthday. Blow them out. - Welcome home.
我讨厌生日，你们都知道的，对吧？
I hate birthdays, you know that, right?
- 对不起 - 生日快乐
- Sorry, sorry. - Happy birthday.
这里还有一封信
This came with it.
亲爱的杰克.莫斯里:
Dear Jack Mosley:
我希望你一切都好
I hope you're doing well and everything worked out like it was supposed to.
我很好
I'm doing great.
西雅图同纽约不太一样，但是我很喜欢这里
Seattle is different, and I like it a lot.
我从来没有呼吸过这么新鲜的空气 这就像一次旅游
I'm not sure I ever smelled fresh air before I got here. It's a trip.
有时我不敢相信，我现在的生活会是如此的美好
Sometimes I can't believe it. It's the best feeling I've had in my life.
虽然现在生活很忙碌，但是我很开心
I'm busting my ass, but I'm happy, though.
我的糕点店也开张了，哈哈
The bakery is now open. Three cheers.
我的糕点店叫做“爱迪和杰克的糕点店” 我把我的名字放前面，因为主要是我在打理它
I put my name first because I'm doing all the hard work.
烤箱很烫的，兄弟
These ovens are hot, man.
希望你喜欢这个蛋糕 我说过会给你做个蛋糕的
Hope you like the cake. What did I tell you?
- 那是爱迪 - 如果你什么时候到这里来了，随时找我好了
- That's Eddie. - Lf you're ever in town, you got a friend.
谢谢你为我做的一切，上帝保佑你，杰克.莫斯里
Thank you for doing the right thing, Jack Mosley. God bless you.
保持联系
Keep in touch. Peace.
- 这太好了 - 再给我拍一张吧
- That's great. - Go on, take one more. Look.
你们知道这个人？ 我刚刚在说话，再来一张
You know how this guy...? I was talking, take one more.
生日快乐，杰克.
Happy birthday, Jack.
-=肯德基英语网www.kfcen.com=- 荣誉出品 本字幕仅供学习交流，严禁用于商业途径